Sander Bell

Web & mobile developer specializing in clean designs, efficient code, and user-centered solutions

I'm proudly a React Native developer at Ling App, a mobile platform for learning languages. With two years of programming experience and over 15 years in communications, media management, and leading editorial roles, I understand the importance of creating concise code as well as seamless, user-centered experiences. I would be delighted if my skills and knowledge could help bring your ideas and projects to fruition.

Experience

Mobile App Developer · Ling · 2023 — Present

Developing mobile UI and logic using React Native

Web Developer · Freelance and Personal Projects · 2022

- Developed a Vue.js application that enables users to count characters and words (<u>somany.ch</u>)
- Developed a React PWA for daily task management (should.today)
- Developed a browser extension used by dozens of people (<u>rewords.app</u>)
- Developed a user-friendly page for checking the air quality in Chiang Mai (<u>cmair.todav</u>)

Editor-in-Chief, PR Executive · **Various Media Businesses** · 2008–2022

- Developed communication strategies and led copywriting teams
- Secured editorial placements and conducted media training as a freelance consultant
- Co-founded independent online media, achieving rapid audience growth
- Created/hosted independent radio and TV programs on IT and socio-political topics

sanderbell.dev linkedin.com/in/sanderbell github.com/sanderbell thesanderbell@gmail.com +66 95 583-40-80

Skills

Fundamentals

CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript ES6, Python 3 Codewars rank: <u>5 kyu</u>

Specialized

Android Studio, Bash, Expo, Figma, Firebase, Font Awesome, Git, GitHub, Jest, JSON, jQuery, Netlify, Node.js, PWA, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, Sass, TypeScript, Vue.js, XCode

Education

Digital Product Design: UX & UI

· 2021 UX Academy

L. S. Vygotsky Institute of Psychology · 2006–2011

Master's Degree in Personality

Psychology and Counseling

Languages

English ****

Russian ***

Thai **

Hebrew **

Interests

AI, Thailand and SEA, Learning Languages, Playing and Listening to Music, Buddhist and Stoic Philosophy, Psychology, Politics, Motorcycle Trips